Good morning, Fujimoto!
Good morning!
You know it's very early.
Yes!
Morning after morning...
what are you here for today?
Yes. I'm here to help, today, too.
Huh?
Fujimoto, I am going to help you.
Oh, man... You know...
Oh?
Good morning, Kobato.
Fujimoto.
Oh, good morning.
Are you helping today, too?
Yes.
Fujimoto, that must be a great help for you.
Give me a break, please! Why should
I need any help from anyone?!
Kobato, don't give in. We're counting on you.
Because at this rate, the moment you
take your eye off of him,
he'll go out and push himself too hard again.
Wha...
Yes!
Kobato.
What should I do?
Even the most obvious of things
Are always such a challenge
I want to laugh when I'm happy
And sing whenever I want
Is all
They say my dreams will come true someday
But when will "someday" come?
I can't wait forever
On "1, 2, 3!" I'll spread open my arms
And let the light gather around me
Where is it?
Please tell me what I can do
I make the most of getting hurt
And run with all my might
Despite how many dozens of times I fall
And start crying
I surprise myself
In how much I believe in tomorrow
Every single day...
I'll do it myself!
Oh that's right.
I found this, so I'll put it
up here for you, okay?
H-Hey, what are you doing?
What else would you like me to do?
...Kobato's Wish.
Where are you headed to today?
Yesterday you went to the library and the day
before that, you went to the university.
I'm going to work.
I've been told that you have
the day off from work.
I've told you time and again. If it's sympa...
It's not sympathy or curiosity.
I thought I told you that you're being a nuisance.
Fujimoto, have you ever taken a walk?
Huh?
Walks are good. They're fun.
The only one having fun...
Fun for you, perhaps.
Let's go.
To where we can have fun.
H-Hey!
That's right. The two of them went out.
You're right.
They just need time, like anyone else.
Just like the two of you did.
What are you trying to do?
What is it?!
Right here, on your face.
It's always scrunched up.
So that's why I want you to have fun.
Boats! Fujimoto, let's get on a boat!
What? A boat? But...
Hey!
It costs money to ride.
Hey, come on.
Hey.
You're going to crash.
Let me do it.
N-No, I can't let you. You're injured.
Then we'll never get back,
no matter how long you try!
No matter how long?
Kobato is ready! I will row with all my might!
Don't dip the oar in too deep.
Right.
Use your legs, too.
Ready, go.
Wow, we're moving!
This is amazing!
So carefree...
Fujimoto.
Huh?
You look a little better up here.
What's the big idea?
Um, I wanted Fujimoto to cheer up,
so I got some food for the fish...
That's not what I'm talking about!
Do you know what predicament you're in?!
Yes. I made him spend money again.
But he did get the change...
I'm telling you, that's not it! How many times
have I told you! We don't have time!
Yes! So I'll do my best!
We'd better hurry back.
Hey! I'm not finished talking with you! Hey!
Hello fish, I got some food for you!
Are you there?
Fujimoto, would you like to try?
Just leave me alone.
I can't relax with you following
me around wherever I go.
I understand.
Come on, let's go, Kobato!
We've got to get as many kompeito as we can!
Hello.
Good afternoon.
Oh, it's just you, Kohaku.
Are you taking a stroll? It's such a
beautiful day today, isn't it?
Aww, what is this overly cheerful atmosphere?!
Is there a problem?
Kohaku! From one carefree to another,
you can lecture her!
Lecture Kobato?
That's right! She's forgotten about her wish
and is fooling around, absentmindedly.
I have not forgotten.
Oh yeah?!
My wish has already been decided.
Well of course.
What is it with Dobato?
I mean, she's just a Dobato.
Are you angry, Ioryogi-san?
You bet I'm angry!
I'm angry, but when she gives
me a look like that...
Kobato has made her decision, hasn't she?
She's a fool.
Nothing happens without purpose.
And therefore, there is not a single
thing that has no meaning.
Is that only true in Tenkai?
Or could you say the same for residents of Ikai?
For every being. For everything.
I see.
Fujimoto!
Oh good. I found you.
Why?
Huh?
Why do you bother with me?
Why? Well, I...
Do you want me to thank you?
Then you're barking up the wrong tree.
Because I don't feel thankful.
And I never will.
Because you mean a lot to me.
It's natural to worry about a
person who is important to you.
Ms. Sayaka has your organ stored away.
I don't care about it.
It's something that you care
very much about, isn't it?
You can go and play it again, any time you like.
What now?
I was just thinking how you and
Ioryogi-san are so much alike.
Like the way you're always angry.
Ioryogi? The doll you're always carrying around?
Yes.
But he's actually very nice.
Guess I'd better get going.
Right.
Kohaku.
You made your decision as well, didn't you?
Are you happy?
Yes.
Oh, what are you doing about your laundry?
It must be difficult hanging it out. I could...
Fujimoto.
What is it?
I cannot be with you tomorrow.
Well, thank goodness. Freedom at last.
If that makes you happy, then I'm happy too.
Take care.
Thank you very much.
Oh, is that right. That's very sudden, isn't it?
Thank you for all that you've done for me.
I would have liked to say goodbye
to Chiho and Chise, too.
I know they'll miss you.
Have you spoken with Sayaka?
I'm planning to see her now.
Oh.
It's been a year now since you came here.
Yes. Four seasons. Spring,
summer, fall and winter.
I had so much fun each and every season.
When you settle down, please get in touch.
Yes. When I settle down.
My wish has already been decided.
Hey Dobato! You do know what
that means, don't you?
Yes.
If you can't fill the bottle with kompeito, you...
Do you not care about what happens to you?
Are you a fool, or what?
Am I a fool?
You're an absolute fool.
One hundred percent.
Ioryogi-san, sorry to keep you waiting.
Are you finished with your farewells?
Yes.
Shall we go, then?
Man, he's not home yet.
Oh well. Perhaps it's better this way.
Look. The moon is bright.
Yes.
You know what, Kobato?
What is it, Ioryogi-san?
Isn't it hard to just be with someone,
without really doing anything?
Hard? Why?
Just being able to be with someone
is a really wonderful thing.
What?!
I presumed you already heard.
No.
Perhaps it was difficult for her
to break the news to you.
Did she tell you where she was going?
No, just that she would be in
touch when she settled down.
There he goes.
He's here.
Wait a minute!
Please, wait! She really did her best!
Yes, she's a bit foolish and
clumsy and an airhead,
and all she has going for her is
her cheerfulness and honesty!
But she's among the best humans
you will ever come across!
She's got an incredible soul!
So I beg you! Please don't eliminate her...
Don't make her... disappear...
Ioryogi-san, you're troubling Ushagi-san.
I'm sorry, Kobato.
Please don't apologize. This is my decision.
I...
Thank you very much, Ioryogi-san.
What are you doing?!
Fujimoto?
Where do you think you're going?
I don't know.
Is this supposed to be a joke?!
You're scolding me right to the last moment.
What do you expect?! What's the big idea
disappearing without a word to me?!
I'm sorry.
Was it something I said?
No! Not at all!
Then, why?!
It's in her contract.
Who said that?!
Over here. On top of the baggage.
Hi.
This is Ioryogi-san.
But... he's a... doll...
I was just pretending to be.
We're talking about the contract, right?
Kobato, show him.
Yes sir.
W-Wait.
What's this about?
What the... what is that?
She's dead.
Kobato's present soul does not
belong in any of our worlds.
It's not a life, just a peaceful existence.
But thanks to a contract with
a particular big shot,
she was given one and only one chance to
be reborn and live life all over again.
Wait a minute! What in the world
are you talking about?!
However...
Kobato chose to spend her remaining time with
you, rather than fulfill the terms of her contract.
And therefore, the contract... was nullified.
And that's why I must disappear.
You're lying! Hey!
Fujimoto, being with you made me very happy.
I can't do it.
I was hoping to stay smiling at the end.
No! Don't do this! I beg you!
Fujimoto.
You are very precious to me.
You have been...
And you will continue to be.
Forever.
Don't go.
Kompeito?
What's this?
The kompeito...
The bottle is filling up.
Kobato's wish has changed.
But the contract cannot be changed.
About going to the place she wants to go.
Fujimoto's... Kompeito...
So warm.
This is more like a curse! Please!
Please let Kobato live in this world!
Darn...
I'm sorry I couldn't be of more help.
Don't apologize. I feel the same way.
I was with her the longest.
And yet I can't do anything.
But if there is a purpose to all that happens...
What is going on?
I have to go where I ought to go.
Goodbye.
Wait.
Nakushita mono to
Atsumeta mono no hazama ni
Anata no egao ochiteita no
Todokisou de todokanai
Tonde yukeru wake janai shi
Warawasete agetai dake na no ni,
Yaku tatazu no kono tsubasa
Nan no tame ni aru no darou?
Anata no soba de warau yo,
Watashi ni dekiru koto
Atatameru dake de mo ii no kana
Semete tsutsumitai
Kizuku no, sono tame no tsubasa to
Ima koso watashi warau yo
Next episode
The Day to Come...
Ima koso watashi warau yo
Next episode
The Day to Come...